## **RUSTAM ISANGULOV**

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER | SOFTWARE ARCHITECT | OCP JAVA 11 | PHD

#### **PROFILE**

15+ years of experience in software development, progressing from a software engineer to a program architect position. It includes 9+ years of working in a Research and Development environment on data processing and planning for automation projects. 6+ years of experience in management and product management in a multi-national corporate environment and in the context of a small startup.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## PRODUCT MANAGER, INTELLISENSE.IO, CAMBRIDGE UK - 2020-2021

Developed product roadmaps, feature specifications and requirements for the brains.app (an industrial SaaS AI platform); Managed effective product delivery by the "platform" scrum team (~12 engineers) to internal and external clients.

## **SOLUTIONS ANALYST, SCHLUMBERGER, BEIJING CHINA – 2018-2020**

Performed analysis of automated planning needs for the well engineering platform (DrillPlan) and investigated potential applications of classical Al planning to improve consistency and procedural adherence.

## PROJECT MANAGER, SCHLUMBERGER, HOUSTON USA - 2015-2018

Managed a team of ~12 engineers with the goal to deliver new decision management and execution system for drilling fluids workflows. On the technical side, I was responsible for multi-domain logical inference design to ensure the new product is well integrated with the drilling automation (see below) and a higher level workflow orchestration systems.

## PROGRAM ARCHITECT, SCHLUMBERGER, HOUSTON USA - 2013-2015

Created the vision, defined technical direction and architecture, and guided technology stack choices for the drilling automation system that is now a part of the well-construction platform (DrillOps). Collaborated with ~30 engineers in the team to ensure a shared understanding of the vision and the plan-based automation architecture.

# SENIOR DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER, SCHLUMBERGER RESEARCH CENTER,

**CAMBRIDGE UK - 2004-2013** 

Developed a number of research projects in the Monitoring and Control Group, mainly concerned with drilling automation, process optimisation and classical AI planning. I have conducted field experiments (to test proof of concept systems) in several locations including Poza Rica, Mexico; Basra, Iraq; Abu Dhabi, UAE.

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER, SCHLUMBERGER, HOUSTON USA - 2000-2004

Developed several commercial software packages as a sole software engineer and as a member of small teams, mainly for seismic and downhole data processing and visualisation.

#### **EDUCATION**

Imperial College London, UK — PhD, Applied Mathematics - 2005 - 2009

Moscow State Technological University "Stankin", Russia — Engineering Diploma (~MS), CAD/CAM Systems & Applied Mathematics - 1992 - 1998

#### **SKILLS**

- Oracle Certified Professional Java SE 11 Developer (28 May 2022)
- Java / JUnit 5 / Mockito / Maven / Spring / Spring Boot
- C# / Matlab / C++ / SQL / Python
- Rational UML Modelling / Planning Domain Definition Language
- Git / Aha! / Jira / Microsoft VSTS

#### **PATENTS**

- Systems and methods for executing a plan associated with multiple equipment by using rule-based inference (US11288609B2)
- Well Construction Management and Decision Support System (US10920565B2)
- Automated sliding drilling (US10883356B2)
- Method and system for directional drilling (US10612307B2)
- Method for calculating and displaying optimized drilling operating parameters and for characterizing drilling performance with respect to performance benchmarks (US10316653B2)

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- Optimizing ROP through automation (Drilling Contractor, Sep 21 2011)
- Increased Rate of Penetration Through Automation (SPE-139897-MS)
- A mathematical model of an oil and gas field development process (European Journal of Applied Mathematics, Mar 8 2010)

4 GEORGE STREET, CAMBRIDGE, UK TEL: +44 7484 310711

EMAIL: <u>RUSTAM.ISANGULOV@ME.COM</u>
LINKEDIN: <u>WWW.LINKEDIN.COM/IN/RUSTAM-ISANGULOV</u>